Finding aid to the Department of French Studies Records CA.MS.00126
Smith College Archives
Department of French Studies Records
1900-1990
Smith College Archives
Smith College. Dept. of French Studies.
CA.MS.00126
0.833 linear feet (2 containers)
This collection contains black and white photographs, meeting minutes, course syllabi and exam questions, and programs.
Biographical / Historical
The French Studies Department at Smith College was established in 1894. Between the years 1899-1901, Italian courses were also included within the department. Its name changed to the French Language and Literature Department in 1895.
Scope and Contents
The Department of French Studies records contain materials describing the department's courses and dramatic productions, as well as information about the French club. Types of materials include black and white photographs, meeting minutes, course syllabi and exam questions, and programs from theatrical performances.
Related Material
Researchers should also view:
RG 42. Faculty
93A-118 Departmental files and minutes, 1950s-1991
95A-74 Departmental files, 1930s-1970s
03A-46 Departmental files, 1938-2001
04A-093 Correspondence, student files, miscellaneous files 1981-2001
These records are unprocessed and portions may be restricted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Department of French Studies records were created by the departments and its students and transferred/donated to the College Archives.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Smith College. Dept. of French Studies.
- General, 1915-16; 1930s-60s; 1990 (Box 1156, Folder 1)
- French club- General, Early 1900s; 1930s-40s (Box 1156, Folder 2)
- French club- Constitution and By-laws, Undated (Box 1156, Folder 3)
- French club- Reports of the Secretary, 1911-24; 1926-31; 1941-44 (Box 1156, Folder 4)
- Courses, 1900s-1950 (Box 1156, Folder 5)
- Courses- 100d, 1978 (Box 1156, Folder 6)
- Courses- 102-200, 1978; 1981 (Box 1156, Folder 7)
- Courses- 201-330, 1978-79; 1981 (Box 1156, Folder 8)
- French 11-46a, 1930s-1950s (Box 1156, Folder 9)
- French Dept. lectures, guests, others, 1941; 1974 (Box 1156, Folder 10)
- Photographs--Courses, 1948 (Box 1156, Folder 11)
- Photographs, 1940s-60s; 1980s-90s (Box 1156, Folder 12)
- Teacher training, 1950s-60s (Box 1156, Folder 13)
- Dramatics- General, Early 1900s (Box 1157, Folder 1)
- Dramatics- Les Deux Sourds, 1901 (Box 1157, Folder 2)
- Dramatics- Les Precieuses Ridicules, 1901 (Box 1157, Folder 3)
- Dramatics- Le Barbier de Seville, 1902 (Box 1157, Folder 4)
- Dramatics- Le Bourgeois Gentilhomme, 1903 (Box 1157, Folder 5)
- Dramatics- Le Voyage de Monsieur Perrichon, 1903 (Box 1157, Folder 6)
- Dramatics- Les Pattes de Mouche, 1905 (Box 1157, Folder 7)
- Dramatics- Le Monde ou l'on s'ennuie, 1906 (Box 1157, Folder 8)
- Dramatics- Le Voyage de Monsieur Perrichon, 1908 (Box 1157, Folder 9)
- Dramatics- Le Malade Imaginaire, 1910 (Box 1157, Folder 10)
- Dramatics- Le Barbier de Seville, 1912 (Box 1157, Folder 11)
- Dramatics- Le Luthier de Cremone, 1914 (Box 1157, Folder 12)
- Dramatics- Songs of Old France, 1915 (Box 1157, Folder 13)
- Dramatics- L'Anglais tel qu'on le parle and Gringoire, 1917 (Box 1157, Folder 14)
- Dramatics- Le Bourgeois Gentilhomme, 1920 (Box 1157, Folder 15)
- Dramatics- Le Malade Imaginaire, 1922 (Box 1157, Folder 16)
- Dramatics- L'Anglais tel qu'on le parle, 1927 (Box 1157, Folder 17)
- Dramatics- The man who married a dumb wife, 1927 (Box 1157, Folder 18)
- Dramatics- Gringoire, 1930 (Box 1157, Folder 19)
- Dramatics- La Folle Journee, 1933 (Box 1157, Folder 20)
- Dramatics- La paix chex soi, Un cliente serieux, 1934 (Box 1157, Folder 21)
- Dramatics- Concert de musique, 1940 (Box 1157, Folder 22)
- Dramatics- Le Bourgeois Gentilhomme, 1941 (Box 1157, Folder 23)
- Dramatics- Les Trent-sept sous de Monsieur Montaudoin, 1946 (Box 1157, Folder 24)
- Dramatics- La Farce de Maitre Mimin and George Dandin, 1954 (Box 1157, Folder 25)